If you're going to configure solar, you
got to do a reduction. Start with the
end goal and work backwards. The reason
you make the solar is to produce power
for something, right? First, you need to
know your voltage and you need to know
your max amperage. Do a load calculation
for a house. Just do a standard load
calculation. There's a [__] section
in the code book. For the purposes of
right now, we have this energy
tank. Now, I'm going to look up the
specs on it cuz that is going to provide
our input. We know it's 230 volts. This
is what I was telling you about the tow
hitch because the residential model
doesn't have a tow hitch. This one does.
So, I think we have the commercial unit
which has a bigger battery and I think
it has a a bigger inverter as well.
We're going to find out, but they could
have just put a [__] tow hitch on the
residential model. He told me they
didn't have any left in stock. Our
inverter specs, max AC charge current,
50 to 240. PV input, here's where we're
concerned. 90 to 230 volts. Max DC
charge current 160 amp. What does that
tell me? I have two separate inputs for
series parallel connection. It all has
to be between 90 and 230 and I cannot
exceed 160 amps between both of them.
That is what I know. I see two inputs
and I know the inverters. I know the
equipment and a single one 80 amps 90 to
230. When I see 160 amps at the same
voltage, I already know it's just wired
in parallel. 94 kwatt hours. It's a 72
volt system. Operates up to 87.6 6
volts. That's a really high voltage. Do
y'all know the difference between
nominal and actual voltage? What voltage
is a 24volt system operate at? If you
put a meter to it, it's usually in the
26 to 27 range. 48 volt system usually
51.2. This one operates
67.2 to 87.6. This is a 72vt system.
Why? Because we're going by 12s. When I
see these higher voltages, that's the
new battery technology. These are a lot
higher. Lithium ion, not lithium ion. 22
kWh battery is a little bit smaller than
a 13 kWh battery to lithium ion. We got
90 to 230. Put that dirt on purpose. 160
amp. That's my PV charging specs. Must
be within this range. I look at solar
like a carnival ride. You must be at
least 90 in tall. Cannot be over 230 in
tall. Cannot weigh more than 160 lbs.
That's just simple. Yeah. Well, it's a
good way to see it. If I see something,
I remember it. I got this pornographic
memory. You see a pornograph.
You log in to failsenergy.com. You come
over here to build a system. You just
have to make a free login. We have to
have an email so we can send you your
free wiring diagram. All right. Now,
fill out this form below. What are our
electrical specs? 10.72 amps 42 42 volt.
Your your Vmax, right? That's like your
operator. Then you have your open
circuit that if you configure for your
operator, it'll work, but then when it
hits open circuit, it'll trip out.
configure for your expected output using
the max figures. You have to configure
your breaker size and everything and
your system based off the short short
circuit value. You got a 20 amp breaker.
Why? Cuz it can't exceed this. But it's
going to really operate around 12 to 15
amps. Play it safe cuz you never exceed
voltage. If we have 230 volts operating
at 42 volts, we can put five in there.
As I put five in there, look at there.
2250 watts. Amps times volts is watts.
I'm going to go ahead and put four in
here because I know what's going to
happen. Add parallel string. Copy value.
1 2 3. I think we can put four on here.
How are we going to wire our batteries?
We have one battery. What's our battery
voltage between 67 87 high voltage cut
off? Let's say when it's full. Amp hours
of
1224. Total battery storage max 106.
Wson always rates his lower than they
are. You're getting more bang for your
buck. Okay. So, what's my DC minimum
input? 90. Okay. What is my max input?
230. Okay. I have one question about the
minimum input, right? Does that mean
that when you're hooking up your strings
of solar panels, if it's less than 90
volts, it won't charge the battery at
all? Submit. Okay. We ain't quite done
yet. I think you need a 12V bus bar. Oh,
definitely a Bluetooth transmitter. And
I can show you where that's going to
wire up. That's going to wire up on your
negative between your battery and your
inverter. What else? Oh, we need a PV
disconnect right here. Well, you can add
anything in here off of this that you
want in my email.
For all your your your solar needs and
design, I let you instead of each one of
these products, I can pick one that I
have used and know works and put on this
website and link it directly. You
literally can use this. It's free. You
made it, right? Mhm. I designed this
whole website. That's Hey, look. That's
me. That's John. Those are the 660s.
There's Nick. There's my [__] van
wearing the same goddamn dirty shorts.
That's me. We are a renewable energy
brain trust dedicated delivering
electric information and power
generation to real people in real
situations. Guys, I I wanted to show you
all this and now that I've showed you
that, you can do it just like I can. You
can give me feedback, too, on how to
make it easier and more and and and
better cuz it's not user friendly to me
yet. When you make a free login, go for
it. Sewing is not that hard and you just
made it even simple. It looks like we're
going to be putting in a max of 7500
watts. How many kilowatt hours do you
need, Julian, to run your uh machine? 40
kwatt hours. 7200 watts going in. Is a 4
1/2 hour sun hour state. Correct. At
four just to be safe. How about 29 kwatt
hours off of 16 of these used panels.
We're only at 42 amps. We can go up to
160 if we do it on our open circuit
voltage at five. Our total voltage is at
50. It shuts off the whole system. So,
here's where we're at. We have our
voltage and we have our ampacity. We're
only operating at 168 volts. That's
beautiful. It's in the middle. It's
nowhere near the top threshold.
42.8 amps. Theoretically, I'd say add
three safely. That'll put us up around
130 something amps. Dude, that's a lot
of [__] juice. Let's say we add three
sets. That's what that is capable of
producing in a day in a real life
scenario. Y'all know about residential
AC electric. Take a panel here. And all
you do is pull some circuits out of it
and put it in a sub panel over here. Put
a 50 amp plug coming into it to feed
your main. Put a 50 amp plug and outlet
coming out of the grid. And you take the
AC charger and plug it into the grid.
Then you take the AC output and plug it
in to feed your sub panel. It's charging
off of the grid, but what you do is set
it to only charge during off peak hours.
So you only buy the cheap energy. You
can cut your energy bill by 50%. All you
have to do is select the circuits, do a
load calculation, figure out this is
what I'm using. I'mma put this in here.
I'mma run I'mma run all this. And if you
hook solar panels to it, then you have
the security of under the grid, but
you're running your AC, your fridge, all
your [__] off of solar. You ain't
worried about selling them energy back
for 30 cents on the dollar. So they pimp
me out to my neighbor. I'm pimping you
out, bro. It's called [__] karma,
bro. If you burn dead animals and
[__] nuclear power to make
electricity so you run an air
conditioner, you're just sorry, bro.
Like in my opinion, I'd rather switch.
We're smart enough nowadays like